welcome to
saturday morning table where we talk
about our projects
and give you an update so we need help
with
is there anybody who'd like to start
i can start i got a quick one i haven't
been working on my projects
at all uh so uh and i can't think of
anything i really need help with
right now so nothing
but who's next
i guess i can go next all right my
project is wiki election
uh meant to fight misinformation in
politics science and news
i've been working with matush on the
prototype um
might have to ask him to skip this thing
he's trying to do because
it seems to be overkill for the
prototype and it's making things take
longer than
i was hoping um so hoping to get that
moving forward
soon and then once the uh current
version that's being worked on is online
uh we'll be pivoting to
get con varadi online which will be
similar to wiki election but uh it's
gonna be for organizations and sort of
emphasis on just
the generic parts of wiki election sort
of the
as i said the organization news content
review
that sort of thing uh so we'll be
starting on that and then
probably more focusing on confronting
because the content review is sort of
the first thing to start with
so uh hopefully pivoting there
or just having the prototype online if
it's done that
you know in the current way but i can't
think of anything i need help with
that's not already behind
all right i'm jubilee and my project
is myself i'm my own project
because it changes week tweak but
solution raising this last week uh
we didn't actually hold the solution
raising we had it on relationships and
i showed up and no one was there right
away and i was not really in the mood so
anyway people call them came in late but
i wasn't there so we're gonna re-hold
the solution raising this wednesday
i feel like the universe gave me the
week off because we also cancelled
yesterday last minute
uh because i had a my kid had a play
date that was only able to happen that
day
and then bentley wasn't able to come so
it made sense to cancel it
seen as what we're working on needs all
of us um
i've been just playing with in my head
the
anti-mlm mlm that and what that looks
like and how i
how i get people involved they can help
create that
so that i'm not doing the work from
myself all of it myself
because i don't i can't do that part so
i don't really know exactly what i would
need help with because i don't know how
to communicate what i would need help
with i need someone to help right thing
i need someone to help make it pretty i
need someone to
help um actually do the executive
functioning of writing [ __ ] down
and making it look pretty but that's
where i was almost late to this because
i was
i was working on something for it so
that's where i'm at this week
cool i did um have
an idea i want to run past everybody and
this is probably more of
a friday thing than a saturday
thing you know um you know we've been
talking about like project directories
and such like that
and there's a thing called the
murmurations
network where you on your own website
you can put data
about your project and then anyone can
then build a directory of these projects
so that you're not having to update a
central
database or multiple central databases
for projects
but what i don't like about that is it
takes a bit of technical skill and a
website so you have to have like
wordpress or something
um so i often think about like jubilee
in situations like this that it
you know it wouldn't be something that
you would be able to
to do easily enough um so i was thinking
it'd be nice if you could literally just
have any website that you or that you
have access to where you could just put
text in
and it'd still be searchable through
google to find
the thing oh i i put this text in about
my project and it's machine readable
and can be put in a directory but still
be kind of human writable
although i guess one of the problems
with that is that like you can't put it
in facebook
because for the facebook is an index the
individual pages aren't often indexed by
google
um and
if they were it would still be hard for
computers to read because oftentimes
they make it where you have to have a
login or something you can't really get
that data to post up consistently
so i don't know like jubilee there's no
other like
websites that you put data in our social
media things do you use any other tech
other than what facebook to use twitter
i mean yes but i don't can't necessarily
list them all
i use instagram as of recently and i
will go on discord you know as much as i
don't like it
i will figure it out for the right
community in groups
um but solving things just for my
project isn't quite
doesn't quite make sense but it is um
somebody posted in our group about a
project called frontier
or pioneer something along those lines
yeah
um it doesn't look very gamey at all to
me but
the same concept seems like anyway
that's not what we're talking about
but uh yeah yeah so
i guess one thing that like like if we
said okay
there's no central database where you're
allowed to put in your project data for
game b
projects but you go someplace and you
and you write this out
and then go and put the link somewhere
and we'll
index it so i guess theoretically you
could go on medium
create a medium account and post it
there and then you could also use medium
to post about your things
stuff like that i don't know so i just
want to see whether that seemed like an
interesting
decentralized solution
for this project yeah especially for a
medium i mean again i'm not the greatest
because i can't necessarily type it out
but i would from you know what i mean
for that like i
keep up the word document sometimes yeah
i mean it would
it would just be here's a the name of
the project here's a quick description
which i know that's
sometimes the hardest part and then it
would be like
here's the uh categories of this project
you know is it technology is it all that
stuff um
so there'd be and there'd be like a
website you'd go and type in
your data and it would format it for you
and you can cut it and paste it in
medium
um kind of like that's the way the
murmurations network does it but they
give you a json file and it's like well
if i'm not a technical person what am i
going to do with the json file
um so i just want to make it lower tech
and and not to where you have to own a
website but you can
be on someone else's is it this database
associated with
tech well
uh i mean
so it would be decentralized so uh
anyone could then create a database off
of this info
right so i in the end though what it
would be is that
it'd be just like our the the drupal
site that
that we're working on or or the the
knack site or the wiki
um the wiki site but instead of you
going to put in the data
you would put the data somewhere that
you have control of and then you would
just
tell the site about it and then it would
build a directory
and that way you're in control of the
data you don't have to if there's
multiple of these directories you don't
have to go to each one and update your
data you just update it
um so that's kind of the idea it's just
kind of decentralizing it
definitely sounds interesting and
realistically a more game b
ish approach yeah that's what i was
thinking
radic do i need to repeat any of that
you came in halfway through i don't know
if it's clear
what i was suggesting uh
i go to the decentralized database and
it tells me everything i need
[Music]
well yeah it's a little different it'd
just be a text format that you could
type into
medium or what's what's another free
kind of blogging system
ghost oh i'm not familiar with that one
yeah so yeah just any non-technical
person could create an account
somewhere it just it wouldn't work for
facebook it might work for twitter
um and then you know we could you know
anyways that was my idea um
so i just wanted to see if anyone saw
any problems with it like it wouldn't
work
okay right do you want to give us an
update on your project
uh my project is uh waiting
for me to have time um
and actually it's waiting also
for me to get some more ideas about uh
some non-technical um
philosophical things more likely
about the direction um in connection
mostly to what we discussed like
elsewhere on monday uh which
also gave me some inspiration to uh
look in
[Music]
like different directions of where to
get data from
and how to present it and yeah generally
there wasn't much progress on that front
uh
on the other hand there was finally
progress on the
recollection the code is i consider it
done
not tested well enough but done to the
point of
me checking it in uh today and
uh to the where it's
accessible on the web uh
i called it uh most of we talked about
one problem with um not a problem but
one thing about it is uh the
first version of the prototype was built
on slightly different assumptions
than uh then um
like well discovered that what would be
better to to um
make it like and so it's now
kind of uh it's slightly messy inside
but
uh it's going in a very good direction
of
uh being more abstract on the
like backhand side and it's still of
course
the weaker action we discussed but uh
it's also um on the back end uh
slightly different from the first
version so
when i check it in we can discuss and i
can show you what i
mean by all this so progress on that
front
and yeah that's pretty much it
cool
so the other thing reddick is done
talking i
i understand that if someone talks on
facebook and i respond it doesn't
respond to facebook no one responds to
youtube
that's what you were saying in the
background um neil yeah you can come on
in
follow the stream yard link that was i
just didn't want to um
anyone in the facebook group game to be
projects can follow the stream yard link
in that week's um
round table and can just come and join
on camera
i think it might be worth uh noting for
those who
haven't done it i'm seeing a link on the
would it be like the placeholder for it
but not the actual live stream
so you have to like find the other posts
on facebook
sorry there's two posts and the stream
yard is only on one of them
it looks like it i'm not sure if that's
happening for everyone yeah someone
commented before i actually posted the
stream yard link
so it's one comment down than it
normally is but it's not
it's not okay because i see two two
different strings one
one showing today's thing is being
scheduled and says this event is live
now but isn't actually showing it
and then neil's comments first and then
you have the link and then i see the
actual live one
with us wanna post the invite there then
i'll be in um from this computer
yeah it's bizarre there's two posts i
didn't know it did that
yeah you know i saw a different post
come in this
morning i don't know technical issues
well also before when you guys don't
have this part of stream yard but like
when you put it up you can
follow it to the youtube posting or the
facebook post whenever i try to follow
it to the facebook post and it doesn't
it doesn't go there it says that it's
like i think facebook has
other they don't want people going using
other services to go live
on their on their accounts i think they
make it more difficult
and it just pisses everyone off because
it's like right but you can't go live on
multiple things facebook
facebook so other topic of discussions
we can just kind of have
what we would have had the meeting on
friday um
and just talk about uh mission
statements
that is true however i think someone
else was also possibly going to join us
now that we got that all
that all figured out um yeah that is
part of uh
one of the reasons also that we
cancelled yesterday um was that
raymond's for the protocol.love that
we're going through
that we are supposed to all be there
right that is
the important part of it that everyone
even though these are
live and you can always rewatch them
that was part of the
so i didn't also didn't know that piece
of it whether we want to make sure that
we are all there for those things so
whenever anubis can't make it that we do
just push it to the next one and maybe
move something else to that time period
yesterday worked out beautifully like i
said it was like yeah
yeah that's that's probably true we
probably should
delay if anyone can't make it we are a
quorum right now though right because
it's just us four
that's in it yeah yeah and so you're
right we could continue on
and do and do that it's also just a
little bit um
you know later on when we become really
famous and people go back and watch it
they're going to miss this chunk of it
it's going to be on the saturday
that's a good point unless you want to
double you could double post the video
if you wanted to but you're right
i'm fine either way i'm good having an
open discussion or we can go on to
mission i
actually also didn't because i had said
i would look i haven't gotten it i don't
know where the document is so i haven't
actually i've only looked at the
document well we've been
that is a good point so together
look at it look at the mission and and
what's the word rank them
say yes this is i added it
yesterday to your question from a couple
days ago but now the question is
where is that
uh here it was on the link itself right
because i posted it
and then that's the other thing asia are
you able to take on posting the two
weekly videos because with my computer
not able to cut and paste it's
next to impossible and i don't see
myself getting up the next couple weeks
you're the only other person who can
post it
um sure i'll email you you can
use this yeah sure if you can remind me
if i forget because i most likely will
well if friday rolls around and we don't
have a link you just
well i mean like hopefully a few days in
advance so we uh
okay uh yeah so i posted a link
in our local in our private stream yard
chat
uh i think that's an editable link as
well i can't remember
um and then i just noticed steve
put an example mission statement
on that same thing
although it doesn't seem to be written
in traditional mission statement
phrasing
oh you can't copy and paste
and this doesn't allow a live link yeah
um i'm finding
let's figure it out yeah
i do see steve's comment underneath
sound permission statement share with
you
oh that looks like a mission statement
for his project yeah i know it isn't
which is good good to have
sure so people can do they can follow
along when we do the foundational clip
collective foundational documents they
can do it for their own which is kind of
like what we're doing at the same time
anyway
we're doing the other tech well kind of
thinking about it for like the side
in our own projects and whatnot okay
yeah i have it up now
wait do i where'd it go there we go
documents but again i haven't actually
able to look at the mission to to know
which order they would go in
and i don't know with my current brain
fog if i'd be capable of doing this now
but
i'm totally down with sitting through
you guys doing it
yeah and we can just chat around it and
finalize it next friday unless anyone
else has any other
topics they'd like to talk about israel
radic anything
we could also talk a little bit more
about
uh integrating
oh i so i made a post on
so we've had a lot of people kind of
interested in the
matching rating system but then i did a
post
in and i didn't i didn't add people's
names to it and stuff like that
to game b projects and i only got one
response on
scheduling a time to do a regular
meeting about these
the matching thing and i think that
meeting would be good to have
you adrio and radic and then
mark and a couple other people that are
interested i guess
i need to put everyone's name on that
post
or is there any other reason you think
why i didn't get as much
participation was it misleading because
the title changed
i don't know i think plugging people is
good i don't think i saw that one
yeah it's okay
i'm glad to make me call it i did like
it so i didn't see it
i might need to redo the doodle now
because i think it's for
last week so
i'll redo that no i'm trying to figure
out who all should be included in it
i see it in there yeah i don't remember
seeing that yeah
well that's facebook for you know
i looked at the group uh like yesterday
and
um just going from top to
bottom of the post i did not read uh
i did the new facebook is
not very cool anyway um
i was stopped at the
uh nathan's nathan waters
post about uh him wanting to do
something very similar
similar i think to what we are doing
um yeah i was curious about that
because it seems it is very similar in
nature
uh slightly different ideas but um
then again i think he's australian
something
so um
he was saying for game b projects he
tends to start uh commons owned
uh structure oh right open source
with 100 open source products no stock
shares et cetera
yeah it sounded kind of interesting
sounds like he has a lot of
specific things in mind that i'm not
sure what 100 agree with ours
at the very least it might end up being
like another similar one which i'm
personally not against i'd kind of like
to have a couple
different variations live so that we can
you know do some a b
testing that's sort of with boards
because you know there's some things
like everyone having the exact same pay
i don't think that's going to work for
you know for example having lawyers
i don't think it's going to work
yeah plus once again we have a bit of
terminology problems
if you uh
still open sources it technically can't
be for profit if there are not stocks
and shares
um that's two contradictory
things um because
profit goes to stockholders profit goes
to stocks oh
software than chairs that's the that's
the definition
well profit is just the money you have
after your expenses
right uh but for an organization you can
be for profit and you just don't pay
shareholders because you don't have i
just don't think you well no but you
still have owners
um which right but profit
sharing you can't do without
shareholders and stuff like that because
who do you give it to but a company can
be for-profit because that just means
that the company behaves in a way
that you know it wants revenue and to
keep expenses low
well there's a lot of companies that
have revenue that don't have profit
and are not so non-profits have it i'm
just saying that
writing ownership so if one person owns
it or a collective owns it then yeah you
don't need shares the profit goes to
them they can figure that out but if you
have
multiple investors well then how much do
they own then you need to issue shares
and you need to know how much
yeah governance and that's particularly
important for profit sharing because if
you're actually saying like
okay but do i get 100 or 101 dollars
from this profit sharing like the
the exact amount then yeah right there's
gonna be
math involved there and how much shares
and where's it coming from and what
actual cut do you get
as opposed to if it's just hey no one's
got shares because we all own it
you don't get the profit based on your
ownership the profit just goes back into
the company
and hopefully it's got profit otherwise
it's not a very good for profit company
yeah yeah i just there's yeah with the
terminology used there's a lot of
open questions yeah i think there's also
he mentions having everything 100 open
source
and then later says like having like
legal protections and stuff to stop
gaming companies from using our attack
like but it's open source so can't you
do that anyway well you can do copy live
or whatever right yeah
defending how you license it and stuff
like that but even then they could use
it and just
figure out what their lawyers how to
license that one product differently
yeah so i don't see any large
differences between what we're doing and
what he's suggesting except maybe just
some
you know yeah because like same salary
is that
is that everyone gets a
a split of the profits
or does it mean that everyone has a set
salary
right is how you know figuring right
sorry
if you've interrupted you bentley sorry
go ahead it's gonna say that like
anything that is
like what we're doing what he's trying
to do what there's a few other people
doing
the more generic we can make it
right the more that whatever together
tech is it's together tech
it's not deciding on how wikileaks has
its governance or how even if we
own something it might be a different
entity deciding on the governance
deciding on on
um how it's run so that their test a
test be
right say hey which one works better
which one works for how do we have fun
um how do we everyone's making the same
way joey now no one's working you can't
like it's somewhat written set in stone
it's like a constitutional document
we want that constitutional document to
be as as um
centralized for like the central
organization and then it's free for
everyone else and i think that is the
difference that maybe we have come to
over i know i have over the last year of
like right
the more rigid it is as much as i might
like the written like i like that things
are open source like that things are
transparent it's always like there's
always a thing that breaks it a reason
not to be and so having it more just
that it is transparent about the
transparency
or just those those kind of things that
there isn't one person's brain is going
to come up with the best solution it's
about
having multiple structures having
multiple things and then we'll find
out which one works and playing in that
space and i think we are doing that
partly because we brought together our
projects
and right yeah
i kind of like the idea of setting a
range for things like so
this thing everyone makes the exact same
might be sort of
the lowest or highest level in that
range depending on how you
you want to think about it and then the
actual thing in the
you know the foundational document or
like the thing here here's what we're
trying to work towards
is having like you know a cap on the
multiplication of like
lowest the highest paid and saying like
okay so we're saying like
in order to be a part of this it has to
be capped i don't know three or five or
ten
or whatever that cap ends up being but
like you can still
be in the you know the club if you have
a five times pay cap
but like past that you really game b
which even though something like that
was let's say i come in and i'm working
for your organization for an hour a
month and so i'm making 50 bucks or even
a hundred bucks
well i hope that somebody's making 10
100 times right
true yeah it would end up being like
probably an hourly
calculation and true really not not how
some executives are like i'm technically
working all the time
no no that that's not how this works
so i keep seeing this as uh like a node
in the network the network is one but
uh there will be like multiple nodes and
maybe testing uh it's kind of looking at
that but um
what it is is more like people having
their own ideas and feeling better with
some particular set of rules and
way of doing stuff which just fits them
better and they are more productive
if things are set in exactly this way as
opposed to slightly different way over
there
and yeah the network is one but the
notes are
multiple and the important thing here is
and what i would like to see emerge from
this
is uh
the network of nodes that are not
fighting each other
not competing against each other
but more like cooperating and finding
their own niche
that would be ideal i think and for the
nodes are you you're talking about like
almost having
a second one of these that operates on
slightly different
a slightly different rule set and kind
of having them both try to work together
towards the same end like where
where realistic not making the same
exactly the same product because that
would be a waste of resources and energy
but more like um i mean more like
attempting to be a game b corporation
right we're like have the same ish rules
right like
trying to get like not having for-profit
you know uh
not having profit sharing at least not
on like you know a mass scale
with the shareholders that don't work
there
um having a cap on the you know
pay multiplication what whatever you
want to call it
it's like separation of concerns and
of uh some things but um
it's more like uh
being it's like a fractal thing of a
um i mean i see the network as being
uh as consisting of like a
fractal structure where uh there are
multiple
not companies not corporations but uh
more like daos
um which uh group
people with similar interests and
similar um
maybe projects that would ideally be one
project they are working on
instead of having like 100 individuals
working on 100 projects it would be
better to have 10 groups of
10 individuals working on 10 different
projects different enough
uh for them to be useful to stay
different and separate but still be in
um
like contacted enough to
not go directly and try to make better
the same product but better than the
competition just around the corner
right so a network of uh
game b projects game beach right yeah
which is
i wonder if that gets into like
collusion territory technically
because i think it's fine it's like
we're not really in the same industry
yet and it's not like we're price fixing
we're trying to avoid stepping on each
other's toes at least until
there's sort of enough corporations and
people are big enough that like
you know if we get to a point where
there's 10 corporations and they're all
worth over a billion dollars we're like
okay more than one of us can make
cookies now
because we're like we have enough that
we can actually start to compete and
start to have different product
offerings
yeah probably not good to start there
like us both start off making the exact
same tech that's just asking for it to
fail
because i think what we end up with is
if we have something like
converati one of the ways i want to be
able to assess corporations is like
how game b are they right and and have
things like okay what's the
the pay cap and what's the minimum pay
and what's and what's stuff like that so
if you say you know i want to be rigid
and i want to say only people who have
equal pay and the minimum pay is this
etc
great here's the two companies that do
that okay i i want you know
at most of five times multiplication and
pay
okay here's a slightly bigger list
yeah although about this i didn't
um as i commented on this
uh about specifically this part of the
project
uh there is something to
the salary the pay being exactly equal
and what i didn't write because
i thought about it only after i posted
was
um the goal
really is to make money not as important
so
yeah you get paid of course because you
need the money to live but
uh otherwise the motivation should never
be money itself
because it's like working for profit and
that's
for short um thing to say is
that's they may and we don't want
exactly that
so uh it should not be motivating people
to
work and to do stuff the motivation is
the best motivation is always internal
and i do stuff because i want to and
it's useful enough so it's appreciated
by the
network and the public and the
money i get is um less important
this it should be separated it
should be shouldn't be i think that's
the long-term goal
but if it comes down to like okay paying
everyone the same and that means that we
can't get a decent lawyer
then if a lawyer is only willing to work
you know even like if they'll take a
reduced pay but like they aren't willing
to work for 80 000
then i would say then i would say that
we need to pay them more
like that's where i'm and i think
long term yeah we we want to emphasize
people that want to be there and
in theory would work for less because
they're actually doing something that
they want to do and something that they
want to be a part of
but i think that sort of long term like
for now is just to get
you know butts and seats if we decode
her
and we can't find somebody you know
that's super passionate but there's
somebody over here just when they get
paid for work cool let's just get it
built
before we get on board the generation of
uh
generation of people who
really understand what it means to have
internal motivation
and can be also awesome
lawyers and of some whatevers
and be motivated by the stuff
they do because they want to instead of
being paid
then yeah i totally have um it wouldn't
make sense
to be strict on this requirement
uh because the result would be not
getting the best
loyal lawyer help or the best caller
right that you can
because you just you know shut yourself
i do agree with your core concept though
that like you want people that want to
be there
and i think for the most part that will
mean taking a pay cut from a game a
world which you know
if somebody's not willing to do that
yeah maybe i
you know that i think will be a sweet
spot where like to very start with it
might just end up being you're trying to
pay
someone on parity to what they would be
expecting but long term yeah i think
even for lawyers
you can pay them less than you would you
know
a corporate lawyer but not like what you
would
pay the lowest paid person in a gaming
company or even here right because
if we're saying starting wages 80 well
corporate lawyers make well into six
figures so if they made half that
working for this corporation that's a
significant pay cut still well into six
figures though
of course ideally you would not need
more
the less rigidity right like what i'm
creating with the i have my own
structure of like 120 000
is the cap and there's these these parts
of it but that is
that things rigidity and so if that
doesn't call in people it's going to
fail
right and if we don't if what we create
with product we create with that
isn't enticing enough to keep drawing in
people then that is going to fail
but having it be what am i trying to say
that all of the different incentives for
all the different nodes
is like right where do i choose to put
my labor where do i choose to go and
that's where
the less rigidity there is like if i'm
amazing at something but the pay
structure is off for me it's like how
can i
do i then create a competing product do
i then
and it's like it all interplays in the
ecosystem
of like the more we can bring it down to
the nodes and bring it down to write as
an
individual how am i incentivized and i
think that
the less we try to what is like
either blanket that and say everyone's
incentivized the same
or make it very rigid that like you have
to like
it's not going to be able to fix the
problem because it's not going to be
able to be as
fluid as it needs to be to be like like
i don't i want my money and needs to be
separate than my purpose and my
and what i'm what i'm doing with my life
because they don't work for me when
they're intertwined
but for other people it might be the
opposite right it's like no i'm not
gonna get
be happy at all unless you pay me i'm
choosing to focus more on the internal
motivation
of sticking with what you want to do for
free
and then if you can get paid for it
great but if you're never paid for what
you're going to do for free
you don't care what everyone else is
doing and i'm talking to someone
on monday who has a somewhat similar
project about the
the data and and selling your you own
your own data and you sell it and i'm
like
i don't because then you're just gonna
like whatever it's breaking the
incentives in my brain because i'm like
wait then am i gonna sell it to
for-profit companies or am i gonna sell
it for cancer research
am i gonna like where am i actually
gonna put it it changes the whole
incentive
instead of like right game is [ __ ]
let's just trade a whole new incentive
where we're not necessarily paying
people and it's volunteer
because like what is volunteer versus a
hundred thousand dollars
right if you have volunteers working for
you and someone making 120 000
that's an infinite increase so it breaks
the game b
but no it doesn't because volunteers are
a completely different
system right than people who are who are
getting paid for something but anyway
i'm rambling on
and there's one more thing actually
because uh
and that's that is some foundational
assumption about
um incentivizing and
money and uh and everything the this
idea of money has been um
actually something real enough
so we when we talk about it
it's talking about salary but um
jubilee you said something uh that
actually
it made sense like the other way around
as in
people usually um
want better money because of something
it's not
just you know i mean i don't know about
lawyers they might be just satisfied
with
you know the number uh on the screen
on the bank account it may mean
something to some people
but uh maybe generally it's
uh and for most of the people it's
slightly different
and they are motivated to get salary in
range of
200 000 for example but not because they
want 200 000 but because they
want what they really want is a
house that is specifically this and this
is
so expensive that they need 200 000 but
uh this slightly changes the perspective
because
if what they want is this big perfect
house
maybe in some future
uh what can be
changed with enough resources and if the
network is big enough
and if we actually
start talking about motivation and
internal motivation and
why even i want the very big house which
costs
that much money that there is something
something there and maybe the solution
is
not to give people
and talk about giving 200 000 but
instead
talking about uh how to provide them
what they really
really want and ideally uh how to
uh i was going to say how to get them to
uh
get to the real motivation because even
behind
having a very big house with you know um
and very expensive maybe there is some
other internal
motivation hidden behind it right so
there are multiple layers of why right
so are you talking about like the
internal motivations that
that that you were talking about before
where that is sort of the
the most ideal employee is somebody
who's super interested in the project
and the company and all that stuff and
like
in theory they work for free if money
weren't
an issue but because they have to eat
you know we still have to pay off
um so that's like the top of the stack i
think almost everybody would agree
with that um and then what i think i'm
hearing
is like okay so if our goal is that
but we still need to make sure people
can eat and have a roof over their head
is having something like a campus where
you're like hey
if you want here's you know a block that
the organization owns that has you know
like apartments it has this and has that
so you know maybe you're only making 80
or 100 but like
your room and board and this and then
all that's paid for so you're like oh
okay now
you're making less but you're net
sort of like what you've got to spend is
more because
well yeah i'm not making as much money
but i also don't have to pay rent
which right there it's like you're
making more money yeah i know i've been
hearing
that like i would love that i would work
at a company
like that in a second assuming that you
know it was a
a a nice place and they allow dogs and
blah blah and these same things that
they go into
deciding where to live but if that were
an option
i think that would be cool and i know
i've heard that from a number of people
both from like the
i want to work there and i want to start
that company
i've heard both yeah it's
i i wonder if i make it uh like
very clear enough because i um
the idea is that um
we are not discussing how much money we
are not discussing money at
this point what we are talking about is
uh
fulfilling uh needs of the
people who uh because
motivation even internal is like two
different things
one is uh what would you be doing uh
if you didn't have to earn
any money if all your needs were
just fulfilled like the house you want
the
yacht you want the car you want every
you have everything what you do
and that is the real internal motivation
which is
i would like to be coding this
regardless of
whether i have something or not and if i
don't do this
if i wanted to if i don't want sorry
if i don't work on what i really want i
don't because
only i need to work for enough
money elsewhere to just you know have
all my needs fulfilled
and the other internal motivation is
for some people it's enough to have like
basic shelter
i mean normal house and normal food and
a car that is a
uh something basic not
rolls royce or something so um and some
people
for whatever reason uh they
don't feel good enough about i don't
know about themselves or about the world
or about
anything if they don't have the ferrari
if i want to have a ferrari that's what
i want and
no period the end i want this
and if i don't have it i will work uh
i will need to work for enough money to
in order to be able to get it
so the question then is uh well first of
all
um how to get such a person to uh
really discover why exactly they need
this this specific car
or do something very expensive uh
because it might be that
uh there is and that's psychology right
so that's one thing and um
yeah and the other thing is
um maybe it's there is some
way of getting the
thing to them this is what they really
want if
this is what really makes them happy for
whatever reason uh maybe there is a way
for the company to actually
accommodate this swish and if the
company owned
a factory of ferraris then it would be
easier to you know okay this is your
ferrari and now
please do whatever you are uh doing
the best okay so i like to
live in i'm gonna be capitalistic for a
second
like i live in that space of like how do
we get our
needs met and our wants and figure that
out without without capitalism
but if it's a company that's doing it
right if it's a company that's like oh
you just need a ferrari why do you need
it yeah we have an extra here you go
um and you're like who do you choose who
to do that for
because if i'm the janitor that
theoretically anyone can do that job
right i'm not a highly skilled but it's
very needed
but i want a ferrari and a yacht and you
know what i mean it's like well you
might not go with me
versus someone who's a lawyer who wants
that so you're really still doing the
same thing
you're just doing it from the other side
whereas if we're
there's something about it if it's the
nodes doing it like if
we're figuring out together oh adriel
wants a ferrari i want a yacht you want
you want a vacation in france and we're
like oh how do we get these needs met
together
those those sound like fun needs but
they're not like tied to our purpose
because i
i like like that internal motivation is
different than the external motivation
and to be able to tear those like why do
i want a ferrari is it so that i have
one and no one else does because that's
not
ever going to be solved in game b
because anyone can have it right so if
it's
i want it because it's fast and pretty
cool everyone could have a fast pretty
car
right like those are different than your
internal motivation is to be better than
everyone else right well
sorry can't be guaranteed but you can
get the
anyway that there's just a difference in
the corporation doing it versus us doing
it for each other
there because a different motivation
like how do you decide who's
got a worthy one and then are they are
they worthy enough
to be someone who we meet their needs
even if when they're extravagant
right and i mean your turn that's
actually one thing that game
has solved is that okay you control that
just by how much we pay you and how much
you make
great you go figure that out any ques
like any questions about how do we
decide who gets a ferrari that's 20
years down the road
right that's like the if the company
actually has enough resources
so i think like there's two very
different conversations there's what do
we do you know today slash over the next
year or two
and then there's what are we working
towards and i think the what are we
working towards yeah it's like it's
less emphasized on the salary hopefully
having other benefits that
are sort of you know communal and the
company can do this at scale we're like
hey
we have a billion dollars yeah there's a
lot of stuff that that
that we can do to improve the lives of
our employees for way cheaper than just
paying the money
and they still see a benefit and
everyone gets the same benefit and then
hey we've got more money to spend as a
company to grow
and hire even more people great
and so i think that's an important
distinction both with like the
planning you know the specifics on how
we're going to operate and then also
like the
core values more
should just work for both as much as
possible like the short term
and long term and if they don't then
admit like hey
if we have this value it might prevent
us from launching but five years down
the road you know we should
consider it or however that might work
and one thing about game a also and
ferraris is
that um a ferrari is a symbol
status and um it's not
when you see it when i see it it's not
as much as a yeah that's a fast pretty
car but it
it's something more and that something
more is actually
uh well to the advertisement taught us
to think about the
this thing because in itself it's a fast
car which is impractical
it's expensive and i don't even have
a route i can drive it to the full
capability of the of the car so it
doesn't make sense for me to have it
and still i want it but why because
well because i've been motivated
and it's totally external so that is a
parallel
uh thread of
additional work for a game b company
which would be ideally providing
services
to um immunize
people from advertisement and to uh
really like make them um understand
their motivation
and possibly fix this to the point of
okay you won't do this but is it the
best
is do you want it just because you've
been uh kind of cursed
to uh to want it or is it because
it's something you really need and it
might be
that uh you know i myself would be happy
if the company uh
could provide the ferrari to some person
who really
wants it and i would see it as
oh okay i would see it as
um i wouldn't look at it as something
uh as a symbol of status i would look at
it as
not pity the person who wants the
ferrari for whatever reason but i would
still see it as
okay some people want the stuff which is
totally impractical
that's their kind of
problem but if they really really need
it that's uh the cure the temporary cure
uh for the symptoms is to just give it
to them
uh and then later on we can discuss uh
the real cure which is uh
going inside the head and then you know
fix whatever is
wrong there let's also keep in mind some
people just like cars yeah
if you just want to fry because you're
like that car is so sexy cool all right
yeah and that might be what you're
working towards although you might
in that case you might i mean some some
of the idea i don't need is ownership
but also just
you know maybe if there's a fleet of
cars and you have a special weekend
coming up you can borrow it yeah
you'll take care of it totally and that
is part of knowing why you want it right
do you want to drive it
on your birthday or do you want it yeah
exactly
do you want to erase it because then we
can just rent a racetrack and take
everybody that wants to do that we'll do
that once again
oh wow exactly cool yeah and i like i
like the idea like the uh
not necessarily getting rid of marketing
because we don't have control over game
a
but there's a certain what you said is
true right that if
like i it doesn't matter what position i
am in in society
if my needs are like right i need a
ferrari and i need a mansion i need this
and i need that like pity that person
because that
person like that like it's it's a
different it's like
they have a greedy disability it's like
they are really hurting for that status
for those things they can't find
because it's like right i have things
that i really love and want and maybe it
is a car maybe it is a house maybe it is
that
but when you you need to have all the
things that need it so that other people
don't have them you're never gonna be
happy
like if you want a mansion in a world
where no one's cleaning your mansion for
you
do you really want a mansion do you
really want that big of an upkeep right
no i want a small
giant yard no gardeners have fun with
that exactly and so it becomes like
and so it's like not even we don't have
mansions it's like
we're not building new ones you go flip
in one of the ones other people have
abandoned
and when you realize that's not for you
and then figure out
how you want to work with the
housekeeping and gardening and
everything else situation
you figure you figure that out and you
let us know how it works for you
yeah it's like a bunch of co-workers
living together being like i'm the
gardener
i'm the chef that sounds sweet i'll live
in that mansion
it seems like the metric there is really
the long-term
mental health and satisfaction of the
people involved and like radix says
sometimes
you know there might be a situation
where we give them a ferrari because
that's where they are at
and maybe they need to drive it around
and not be able to repair it or
something for a while you know
or just you know that may be the long
thing but also sometimes the long-term
thing would be like well we're not going
to
supply that now who makes that decision
and everything that's something that's
an unknown
problem that's a problem we have no
solution for yet but something to work
on
yeah so something else that seems kind
of worth to
to bring up here because it seems
relevant is what i was thinking of the
whole like
worker cooperative versus consumer
cooperative
thing and i agree with jubilee's notion
that like for a company it makes more
sense to be a consumer cooperative
because then that sort of you know
encompasses you're actually selling
things too to make sure that you're
getting the most
useful information but it seems that in
that model a worker cooperative could
sort of become the union
and i wonder how much it's just okay the
corporation deals with that union says
here's you know how much money you get
you figure out amongst yourselves how
you want to divvy that up and what the
you know
the benefits are and then if the union
gets big enough we're like hey we you
know
are this union for a 10 billion billion
dollar company we have two
billion dollars to spend all right you
know once a year we're going to go
rent a a a racetrack and a bunch of cars
because we can afford it
if that's something that like okay are
there enough people here who want to
drive cars
cool that's your benefit and then you
know
three months later you're gonna rent a
yacht no you don't get to do all of the
things because there's
limited capacity and you have to pick
or something like that right like it can
work it out and where it's not
necessarily up to the company
it's like the company's job is just to
you know to basically make profit
and keep it within it so that it keeps
growing and so they can keep
giving money to that union and pay its
staff
and then it's up to the union to decide
on the pay cap to decide on
um you know all the extra
benefits that aren't exactly
salary-based
yeah if i if i could redirect in the
last five minutes
um one things that i was thinking that
we need when we have this together tech
is kind of a decision making tool but
a way to say okay if you're donating
your 25
dollars a month or whatever we said how
are we as a group gonna decide
where that money gets spent so i thought
it'd be nice to have some sort of
ongoing survey tool that says here are
here the project ideas anyone can throw
in an idea
here's the people that want to kind of
support it and stuff like that
is that something we should build on in
the short term
like if i'm putting 25 and i'm deciding
where that 25 dollars go or is
collectively we're deciding where the 25
dollars goes collectively
i don't know yeah it would be either
um but i think it would be just kind of
way to get a sentiment of all the
participants on where they would like
so if we get a new project how do we
kind of get feedback from everyone that
hey that's a good idea or that's
something i would use
um that sort of thing and then later we
can work out the specific rules but yeah
or is there are two already out there
that that does that that's cheap and
easy i think it is breaking
down for that piece right are you using
it how much are you paying for it where
are you like
if we're if we're paying 25 into a pool
part of that pool is that it needs to do
somewhat what a government does right
like would you choose for your tax
dollars to go to roads maybe not
right like even though you use them
constantly it doesn't feel like it's
something that you want to put money
towards
if your kids aren't you know you don't
have kids in their own school like it's
i'm not going to put money towards
education
and those things come up time and time
again when we're creating game b
right the scheduling app the wikipedia
all these things that aren't necessarily
income generating and then it's so it's
like the same thing happens if we're
incentivized to only do what's
what's like going to be a benefit for us
then it's going to be all the big
projects that get things
and that's good to be the ones with the
most impact but there's going to be
fringe ones that need
so it's like if we could
like rank them in importance right oh
this needs to get done potholes need to
get filled
roads need to be done whatever our
equivalent of that is right admin work
this stuff needs to get done even if
it's not sweet and sexy
and we're probably gonna need to pay it
because it's not sweet and sexy and so
it's like that there's a way to possibly
break it up where you are like what am i
gonna use
what's the most important what are all
these projects needing right
we all need the potholes filled we all
use the roads it's like how do we
yeah i like the idea of being able to
vote on that and also be able to see
just the bigger picture
yeah i think you kind of need a
combination of both
where you've got like okay if you give
you know 25 a month okay
10 of that you you know or 15 i'm not
sure which way it would go
but like a slice of it you get to vote
on like
exactly where it goes like oh i'm going
to fund those two projects great we're
going to take that amount and split it
or you can say i want 80
here and 20 there cool you have full
control and then everything else goes to
the
organization the corporation or whatever
where it spends it still
within lines of you know what that
corporation's charter says it's not like
hey let's go start drilling for oil
well if that's in the charter i guess
but odds are it won't be um
and so that then it's up to the like
sort of
that group to say as a corporation
here's what we need so if
the corporation needs roads even if
nobody's voting for it we're like okay
but we all agree that we need roads
great we're going to spend the money out
of that out of that pool
or that's a bit more like taxes as
opposed to like
donations you kind of have both sides
but try to streamline it so like you you
just give us 25
a month well but 10 towards the projects
that you say that you want to spend it
to
then 15 towards the infrastructure the
salaries the
you know anything else that we sort of
need to keep this ship afloat
yeah out of a hundred
hundred uh they would be able to say for
example
um the ten percent is uh like fixed
and that's going towards the uh
cooperation uh and then
um maybe 25 percent uh for specific
projects that
the main person would like to see
done and then more than 25 percent
towards
like a set of projects that uh
the person considers worth actually
doing sometimes
flexibility right
yeah it sounds a bit like we need to
offer
like to support projects in different
ways like i was thinking of
you know for example if you had you know
projects like reason score and
wikilection
and hyper logo so you're like they're
tech they can get fairly large and they
can spend quite
a bit of money no problem but then like
if you had like an animal sanctuary
well if you give an animal sanctuary you
know 10 million dollars
you can open another animal sanctuary
maybe like it's not it's not quite as
scalable so
it seems like there might be multiple
types where you're like okay if you're
just like
i don't know what you call it a
maintenance one you set
what your expenses are and then like
okay we're not really
going to give you much outside of that
so if somebody says i want to give money
to animal sanctuaries great
it goes into this pool that gets then
spread out amongst the different animal
sanctuaries
where they go through a review to say
okay what are your expenses and how big
is it and how many animals and blah blah
blah
try to figure out the best ones and then
that's done
in a bit of a different i don't know any
structure out there like that but so
that it's not like okay there's one
animal sanctuary that's just killing it
on patreon and making
50 000 a month and then this other one
that's just as big as making ten dollars
a month
but they're just maybe not as good at
content
so to hopefully take that part of it out
and say like if you just want to try to
get maintenance and just try to like
cover your expenses yeah we can totally
help with that we're not here to make
that
part of like we aren't here to make
animal sanctuaries profitable we're here
to you know
keep them afloat if that makes sense yes
yes yes
i think that's something we do have to
stop but similar to what you had
mentioned that mark
likes um like the complexity of it how
much is it gonna cost what is it like
breaking it down to that and you can see
if something's cheap and high impact
that's what we're starting like that's
where the money should go but then
there's also gonna be things that are
that are
extremely expensive and high impact
clearly the highly expensive low
impact ones are gonna be the ones that
we don't do for a very long time until
they become more impactful right once
that niche of people really needs that
once that then it's going to be and
possibly makes it cheaper to make it to
right with everything else that's being
created but
there's a lot of options the more we can
play with them instead of being legit
about them and making it be
one way like when i'm working on the mlm
where it's like five dollars goes to
that structure
any like it could be voted out well then
it's gonna break the whole thing
but also if we don't create something
amazing
and if people don't like the idea five
dollars is always going towards that
they could just recreate a new one and
be like hey actually let's do like
that's part
of the part of it if what we create
isn't good enough
then anyone can reproduce it and create
it and tweak it and make it a little bit
better it's just is it just
right yeah it's just like that one
except for these two things so if you
like this better come over here
yeah i definitely like that idea of like
if you don't like it go start your own
like this this should need to support
the ability of there end up being you
know
five or ten big versions of these like i
think that's kind of the ideal world
where you end up with a bunch of these
massive game b corporations
that work together but still kind of
compete but you know like
if you lose a million people to go over
to one you're like yeah at least they're
still in the ecosystem
that's why the less rigid we can be
because that's actually
if there's multiple game b corporations
actually competing with game a it's not
going to necessarily be able to get out
compete game a but the more that that
whatever that central
whatever that thing is that needs to be
there's necessary to be central
but the more it's inclusive
and can be more generic and can be more
something that you can play in
where you're not going to be enslaving
people and drilling for oil but it's
like
anything of anything's allowable within
you know like i can't say that 25 is the
ethical amount
of 50 feet is like there's you know what
i mean like you're playing with numbers
it's like there isn't really a reason to
do one and not the other
that you're trying different iterations
and i lost my train of thought and we're
past the hour anyway
but that is the point because then
you're not competing right this is like
right you can you can make a wiki
election that competes with wikilection
but whatever together tech or whatever
that entity is that someone else does
that
like there is a point i think where
there needs to be one of those because
it makes it much more efficient to be
like
oh one place the people are one central
database one thing
i think the market should define that
right like if a competitor comes out for
wiki election and it's got one percent
yeah you can stay afloat
maybe if you have funding issues sorry
see you later but if it like comes up
you know it's got 20 or 50
or 80 market share all right that's like
if we're playing with numbers where
where both can stay afloat
then there might actually be a need
there might be something that one is
doing
different that will never be like if
that one drops those people won't come
over
and no to the central right whatever the
thing is that because
if there's if wikilection has to choose
between 15 different organizations to
decide which one it's part of or it's
part of all of them
you know i mean they were having all of
this [ __ ] happen and it's like not
efficient and not it's like how does
that happen with well it's
well it's not as effective globally
that's still pretty efficient
maybe maybe not but anyway um we should
probably end this
and see each other on friday for the
remission
you